<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20250430</CreaDate><CreaTime>09523200</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><DataProperties><itemProps><imsContentType export="False"/></itemProps><lineage><Process ToolSource="c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\Rename" Date="20250430" Time="111620">Rename C:\Users\maxsc\OneDrive\Dokumente\AppliedGeoinfo\SoSe_25\I3\work\I3_main_analysis_arcgispro\arcgispro_testing_fire.gdb\META_LC_SanDiego_2001 C:\Users\maxsc\OneDrive\Dokumente\AppliedGeoinfo\SoSe_25\I3\work\I3_main_analysis_arcgispro\arcgispro_testing_fire.gdb\META_LC_SanDiego_2021 RasterDataset</Process></lineage></DataProperties><ArcGISProfile>ISO19115_3</ArcGISProfile></Esri><dataIdInfo><idPurp>The goal of this project is to provide the Nation with complete, current, and consistent public domain information on its land use and land cover. Note: The California Department of Fish and Wildlife subsetted the original nationwide dataset to California - some portions of this metadata may still reflect the nationwide dataset.</idPurp><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), in partnership with several federal agencies, has now developed and released seven National Land Cover Database (NLCD) products: NLCD 1992, 2001, 2006, 2011, 2016, 2019, and 2021. Beginning with the 2016 release, land cover products were created for two-to-three-year intervals between 2001 and the most recent year. These products provide spatially explicit and reliable information on the Nation’s land cover and land cover change. NLCD continues to provide innovative, consistent, and robust methodologies for production of a multi-temporal land cover and land cover change database. NLCD 2021 adds an additional year to the map products produced for NLCD 2019, with a streamlined compositing process for assembling and preprocessing Landsat imagery and geospatial ancillary datasets; a temporally, spectrally, and spatially integrated land cover change analysis strategy; a theme-based post-classification protocol for generating land cover and change products; a continuous fields biophysical parameters modeling method; and a scripted operational system. The overall accuracy of the 2019 Level I land cover was 91%. Results from this study confirm the robustness of this comprehensive and highly automated procedure for NLCD 2021 operational mapping (see https://doi.org/10.1080/15481603.2023.2181143 for the latest accuracy assessment publication). Questions about the NLCD 2021 land cover product can be directed to the NLCD 2021 land cover mapping team at USGS EROS, Sioux Falls, SD (605) 594-6151 or mrlc@usgs.gov. See included spatial metadata for more details.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><idCredit>U.S. Geological Survey</idCredit><idCitation xmlns=""><resTitle>National Land Cover Database (NLCD) 2021 Land Cover California Subset</resTitle><citRespParty xmlns=""><rpIndName>U.S. Geological Survey</rpIndName><rpOrgName>U.S. Geological Survey</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Publisher</rpPosName><role><RoleCd value="010"/></role></citRespParty></idCitation><searchKeys><keyword>Image Service</keyword><keyword>biota</keyword><keyword>National Geospatial Data Asset</keyword><keyword>digital spatial data</keyword><keyword>Land cover</keyword><keyword>United States</keyword><keyword>Image processing</keyword><keyword>U.S.</keyword><keyword>NGDA</keyword><keyword>US</keyword><keyword>Land Use Land Cover Them</keyword><keyword>GIS</keyword><keyword>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</keyword><keyword>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS)</keyword><keyword>California</keyword></searchKeys><dataLang><languageCode value="eng"/></dataLang><dataChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></dataChar><dataExt xmlns=""><geoEle xmlns=""><GeoBndBox><westBL>-130.2328</westBL><eastBL>-63.6722</eastBL><southBL>21.7423</southBL><northBL>52.851</northBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><idPoC xmlns=""><rpIndName>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS)</rpIndName><rpOrgName>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS)</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Publisher</rpPosName><role><RoleCd value="010"/></role></idPoC><resMaint xmlns=""><maintFreq><MaintFreqCd value="010"/></maintFreq></resMaint><resConst><Consts xmlns=""><useLimit>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;None. Users are advised to read the dataset's metadata thoroughly to understand appropriate use and data limitations.Disclaimer: The State makes no claims, promises, or guarantees about the accuracy, completeness, reliability, or adequacy of these data and expressly disclaims liability for errors and omissions in these data. No warranty of any kind, implied, expressed, or statutory, including but not limited to the warranties of non-infringement of third party rights, title, merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, and freedom from computer virus, is given with respect to these data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useLimit></Consts></resConst><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="002"/></tpCat><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="007"/></tpCat><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="010"/></tpCat></dataIdInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20250430</mdDateSt><mdLang><languageCode value="eng"/></mdLang><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></mdChar></metadata>
